Alexander R. Wandres

alex.r.wandres@gmail.com | mobile: 301-801-4264

I am a full-stack developer with heavy analytical skills who focuses on efficient workflow, elegant design, and creative solutions in order to optimize productive output. I have a sense for style with a focus on user experience. I am organized and thorough, with a strong work ethic and capable of performing in individual or team-based environments.

Proficient in the following languages and frameworks: JavaScript, AngularJS, React, Node, Express, Vue, Meteor, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS3, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Sinatra

Knowledgeable in CMS: Wordpress, Joomla, and Sitefinity

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Publishing Solutions, Germantown, MD

Website administration

January 2017 to Present

- Post monthly magazine articles in various CMS using HTML and CSS
- Process photography and graphics for web use
- Post web banners using 3rd party ad management software
- Clean up coding and fix errors in HTML on various websites

Le Desales, Washington, D.C.

Server, upscale casual

March 2017 to July 2017

- Brought in to help open a new restaurant for Michelin star rated chef
- Trained new team members to a high standard of service
- Improved logistics and customer experience by implementing a service system to improve kitchen output

STK, Washington, D.C.

Server, upscale casual

December 2015 to November 2016

- Knowledgable of various cuts of steaks and their flavor profile
- Provided a detailed and intimate service experience despite high table turn around time
- Helped the restaurant transition into a 'club' after dinner service

Claudia's Steakhouse, Washington, D.C.

Server, fine dining

June 2015 to December 2015

- Fine dining service with a focus on details
- Train new servers had various managerial contributions to the organization and efficiency of the restaurant
- Focus on upselling the many high end wines and food available on the menu

Ethel's Creole Kitchen, Baltimore, MD

Server, fine dining

October 2014 to May 2015

- Family owned restaurant with a 3 person server staff
- Exceptional food the place is usually completely booked on weekends
- 3 servers handle a restaurant with a 20 table capacity

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Washington D.C. Web Development Immersive Program Attended Fall 2016 to Winter 2017

University of Maryland, College Park, MD 2008-2012 Courses in Philosophy GPA 3.48 Alpha Tau Omega fraternity